Guide to the New-York Historical Society Manuscripts of Lectures and Addresses 1809-1957, 2001, 2015-2016 NYHS-RG 11
New-York Historical Society
- Allan Nevins. The Golden Thread in the History of New York, 1954 November 16 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  Includes Nevins's address and his transmittal letter to N-YHS Director R.W.G. Vail.
- Grayson D. Kirk. The Marquis de LaFayette, 1957 October 30 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  Includes a partial text of Kirk's lecture as released by the News Office of Columbia University. The folder also includes an invitation for the event, which was in conjunction with the N-YHS exhibition LaFayette and the New-York Historical Society.
- Rebecca B. Rankin. The Quintessence of New Yorkism, [1957 November 13] (Box 10, Folder 11)
  Includes Rankin's lecture and the related invitation/admittance ticket for the event, which was held in conjunction with the N-YHS exhibition The Second Hardest Job in the World: Mayors of New York City 1784-1957.
- William Jefferson Clinton. [Reflections on America on the 225th Anniversary of the Declaration of Independence], 2001 July 17 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  Includes two copies of a typescript of the remarks made at the N-YHS event An Evening with Former President William Jefferson Clinton and copies of the invitation to the event. The typescript includes introductory remarks by Kenneth Jackson, Betsy Gotbaum, and Bernard Schwartz; Clinton's remarks; Jackson's questions at the conclusion of Clinton's remarks; and Clinton's responses.
- Firth Haring Fabend. Govert Loockermans: Local Boy Makes Good, 2015 October 20 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  Remarks made at reception celebrating the donation by the Society of Daughters of Holland Dames of the loockermans land patent signed by Petrus Stuyvesant in 1664. File includes the program with an image of the patent and a translation of it.
- Wynton Marsalis. [Remarks on Introducing Ken Burns as 2016 History Makers Award Honoree], 2016 September 26 (Box 10, Folder 14)